<NIKITA AVEROCHKIN>

</FRONTEND DEVELOPER>

+7 915 543 85 25

🔀 aser-14@bk.ru

Voronezh, Russia

Portfolio website

Hey! I'm creative and constantly growing developer with more than three years of experience who loves crafting products that people love. I'm eager to apply my expertise, solving extraordinary problems and bringing profit to customers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

IT_ONE | Moscow, Russia (Remote)
May 2023 — Current

I was developing a corporate application portals:

- Worked on diverse projects: on React.js and on pure ES5 JavaScript.
- Carried out organizational tasks of the team.

I have completed over 30% of request templates that are used by ~700 unique users daily. I accelerated the build time of a React.js project by 200% and improved UX by 40% through optimizing it's performance and redesigning. I created detailed project documentation which sped up the onboadring process by 20%.

Stack: React.js, JavaScript, CSS, Styled Components, Webpack, HP Service Manager, RAD

Frontend Developer

Calendaria | Almaty, Kazakhstan (Remote) November 2022 — May 2023

I was a frontend lead of enterprise portal, including:

- Designing frontend architecture on React.js and application layout from scratch.
- Analysing of technical assignment and project needs.
- Mentored 2 junior developers, interacted with various teams.

I successfully accomplished the full development process within contract period, achieving the main goal of digitizing up to 80% of the company's document flow. My efforts have resulted in an application that is actively used by 4500 employees.

Stack: React.js, TypeScript Redux-toolkit, React-JSS, Ant Design, Webpack

Frontend Developer

Tecom | Nizhny Novgorod, Russia (Remote) November 2021 — November 2022

I was working on several projects: My role included:

- Development of key libraries, including a corporate UI-kit with storybook, as well as a library of readymade utilities.
- Fixing, refactoring and writing new logic on React.js.

 Implement unit and e2e tests to ensure the core application reliability.

I implemented 100% of the core functionality in editorlike widgets and received positive feedback from customers. Due to my tests, I decreased the amount of pre-deployment bugs by 80%. My efforts in developing libraries have made the development process several times more efficient.

Stack: React.js, React-JSS, Material UI, Intl, Redux, Reselect, Jest, Playwright, Ierna

Frontend Developer

Julius | London, United Kingdom (Remote)
December 2020 - November 2021

I was preparing the company's main React.js project for release into production. For this I:

- Redesigned the layout of almost all the components, improved app accessibility.
- Developed many features, such as theming and internalization and components, such as tables and dashboards.

I significantly accelerated frontend development through my SCSS refactoring and theming. Noticeably increased the overall app performance and it's accessibility up to 90%, improved numerous core functionalities and quality of user experience making the app 100% pixel-perfect identical to Figma.

Stack: React.js, TypeScript, SCSS, Ant Design, GraphQL, React Relay

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Voronezh State University

2019-2023 | Voronezh, Russia

Faculty: Applied math, informatics and mechanics. Direction: Fundamental informatics and information technologies

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (FLUENT), RUSSIAN (NATIVE)